A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Office of the City Engineer, Records, 1809-1975
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Architectural drawings and plans, 1809-1975.
  - Map - Map / of Section of City / from / Fourteenth St. to Twentieth St. / Between Main Street & James River / Showing Proposed Route of Roadway, 105-C-2, 1915, Dimensions: 31 x 52 in. - 79 x cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink, blue ink, and red ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: Office of the City Engr. Sept. 1915
  - Map - Chart Showing the Corporation Line of the / City of Richmond, Va. Effective Nov. 5 1914 / Also / Corporation Line Prior to that Date, 89-C-2, 1915, Dimensions: 30 x 36-1/2 in. 76 x 93 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va. / Jan. 12 1915 / J.S. Potts Jr. Del
  - Map - Map of / Monument Avenue / from Roseneath Road / to Horsepen Road, 90-C-2, 1915, Dimensions: 18-3/4 x 53-3/4 in. - 48 x cm.; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: T. Crawford Redd & Bro. / Surveyors & Engineers / Prepared for Administrative Board, City of Richmond, Va.
  - Map - [Reproductions of four historic maps of Richmond from 1793, 1826, 1835, and 1827], 95-C-2, 1915, Dimensions: 34-1/2 x 31-3/4 in. - 88 x 81 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
  - Map - Map of / Richmond / Virginia overdrawn with A Study of the / Future Disposal of Sanitary Sewerage in the West End, 11199-D-1, 1915, Dimensions: 35-1/4 x 60 in. - 89 x 152 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1000'; Media: Bulletin print on linen with colored ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: Original map by Engineering Department of the / Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone / Company of Virginia
  - Map - Map / of / John E. Sheppard Estate / in the City of Richmond Va., 33-C-3, 1916, Dimensions: 130 x 41-1/4 in. - 76 x 105 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Blue line print on linen with colored ink washes and details; Sheets: 1 (Folder 28)
    Drawn By: Map Drawn By / F. Jones
  - Map - Proposed Chamberlayne Parkway / Brookland Park to Broad Street / General Plan Showing the Existing Conditions along the Parkway, 46-A-6, 1916, Dimensions: 23 x 122 in. - 58 x cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Brownline print with ink and colored crayon notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: Bolton, Clarke & Pratt / Incorporated / Civil Engineers Richmond, Va.
  - Map - Grade Chart / from Forest Hill Ave. and Semmes Ave. / to James River / and from / 1910 Corporation Line to Forty Third St., 10787-D-16, 1917, Dimensions: 42-1/2 x 73 in. - 108 x 185 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 1)
    Drawn By: Office of Annexed Territory Survey / M. O. Hankins Chief of Survey
  - Map - Map of Block Bounded By / Park & Grove Aves. - Harrison & Morris Sts., 118-C-2, 1917, Dimensions: 22-1/2 x 29 in. - 57 x 74 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink, red ink, and yellow ink, on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
    Drawn By: City Eng'r's Office / Richmond, Va. / April 14th 1917 / Survey and Map By / Fontaine Jones / Ass't City Eng'r.
  - Map - Plan / of / Proposed Sewer System / From 1910 Corporation Line to 1914 Corporation Line / and from / Maury St. to James River, 11290, 1919, Dimensions: 43 x 62 in. - 109 x 157 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 10)
    Drawn By: Richmond Va. / Department of Public Works
  - Map - Map of / the / Manchester Commons / and Adjacent Property Containing Approximately 29 Acres, 10952-A-3, 1920, Dimensions: 27-1/2 x 93 in. - 70 x 236 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: 1 Pencil and India ink on linen, 1 diazo print; Sheets: 2 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: Department of Public Works / Chas. E. Bolling, Director / M. O. Hankins, Asst. Eng.
  - Map - Map of / Richmond / Virginia, 11238-B-2, 1921, Dimensions: 29-1/2 x 30 in. - 75 x 76 cm.; Scale: 3/4" = 1000'; Media: Printed map with colored crayon shading; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: bureau of Design
  - Map - Map of / Eastern End of Laburnum / Home Tract / Showing Proposed Street / Being a Portion of Laburnum Tract, 1200-B-4, 1921, Dimensions: 29-1/2 x 29-1/2 in. - 75 x 75 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 2 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: J. Temple Waddill / Civil Engineer and Surveyor
  - Map - Compiled map of several tracts of land / owned by Geo. W. Gregory, situated at Westham in Manchester District Chesterfield / County Va, 11281-B-3, 1922, Dimensions: 17-1/4 x 27 in. - 44 x 69 cm.; Scale: 1" = 330'; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 7 (Folder 28)
    Drawn By: W.W. LaPrade & Bros. / Engineers & Surveyors
  - Map - Topo Survey of Area Between / 17th. St., 9th. St. Road, Maury St. / and 1914 Corp. Line Covering Prop. / of C. Redford, Davis Brick Co., & Riverview Place, 11212-C-2, 1922, Dimensions: 39 x 32-3/4 in. - 99 x 83 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
  - Map - Topographic Map of / Eastern End of Laburnum / Home Tract, [No file number], 1922, Dimensions: 29-1/2 x 22-1/4 in. - 75 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: J. Temple Waddill / Civil Engineer and Surveyor / Richmond, Va.
  - Map - Map of / Va. State Fairgrounds / Richmond, Va., Y-80, 1926, Dimensions: 39-1/4 x 39-1/4 x 60-3/4 in. - 99 x 154 cm.; Scale: 1" = 60'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 1)
  - Map - Record Map of Windsor Farms on the james River/ at /Richmond, Henrico Co., Virginia /made for /Windsor Farms, Inc./ Richmond, VA/ by /Allen J. Saville, Inc.,/ Engineering and Construction, Y- 12525/H-141, 1926, Dimensions: 137 x 162 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 7)
    Drawn By: Allen J. Saville, Inc./Engineering and Construction
  - Map - Tentative Layout / of / Terminals / and / Railway & Highway Connections / for / Enlarged Harbor Facilities / at / Richmond, Virginia, Y-1631A, 1928, Dimensions: 32-1/2 x 60 in. - 82 x 152 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 1)
    Drawn By: Department of Public Works / Bureau of Survey and Design
  - Map - Henrico County Adjacent to Richmond, VA, Showing Development, Y-4522, 1930, Dimensions:; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: Blueline print; Sheets: 6 (Folder Roll 20)
    Drawn By: T. Crawford Redd & Bro. Inc./ Civil Engineers
  - Map - House Number Map / City of / Richmond / Virginia, [No file number], 1930, Dimensions: 37-3/4 x 44-1/4 in. - 96 x 112 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1000'; Media: Printed map on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder Roll 1)
  - Map - City of / Richmond / Virginia / and / Environs, [No file number], 1933, Dimensions: 47 x 28-3/4 in. - 120 x 73 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1600'; Media: Printed map with colored pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
    Drawn By: Prepared by / Department of Public Works / Bureau of Survey and Design
  - Map - Richmond's Port Development, Y-5562, 1939, Dimensions: 26-1/2 x 67 in. - 67 x 87 cm.; Scale: 1" = 500'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 1)
  - Map - The / James River / Development / Project, Y-5563, 1939, Dimensions:; Scale: None; Media: Blueline print on heavy fabric; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 18)
  - Map - Richmond Airfield / Richmond, Virginia / Utility Map, [No file number], 1942, Dimensions: 42-1/4 x 63 in. - 107 x 160 cm.; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 10)
    Drawn By: U. S. Engineer Office, Norfolk
  - Map - Richmond Airfield, Richmond, Virginia/Electrical and Telephone Distribution Systems, Y-10025, 1944, Dimensions: 107 x 160 cm.; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: Blackline print; Sheets: 1 (Folder Roll 10)
    Drawn By: Corps of Engineers, U. S. Army
  - Map - City of / Richmond / Virginia / & / Environs, Y-6712, 1975, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1" = 1/4 mile; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder Roll 17)
    Drawn By: Department of Public Works / Division of Engineering
  - Map - Map / of the town of / Barton Heights / in Henrico Co. Virginia, 23-D-4, n.d., Dimensions: 33-1/2 x 39 in. - 85 x 99 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
  - Map - Map / Va. State Capitol / and / Surrounding Square / Richmond, Virginia, 37-B-4, n.d., Dimensions: 26-1/4 x 37 in. - 67 x 94 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 92)
    Drawn By: Traced by Fontaine Jones
  - Map - A Delineation of the Oil Fields / of / Cumberland and Clinton Counties, Ky. / and Clay, Puckett, Jackson and Overton Counties, Tenn., 12-D-1, n.d., Dimensions: 23-3/4 x 30-1/2 in. - 60 x 77 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: By / Jno. W. Otley / Structural & Suggestive Geologist
  - Map - [Map of central Richmond showing drainage conduits], 17-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: 22-3/4 x 36-3/4 in. - 58 x 93 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink, red ink and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 26)
  - Map - Plan / of the / Division of / Richard Adams' Estate, [No file number], n.d., Dimensions: 37 x 52 in. - 94 x 132 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Ink and colored inks on paper with heavy cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder Super-OS 4, Dwr. 3)
    Drawn By: Made expressly for their own use& W. F. Pleasants S.H.C.
  - Map - Richmond, Virginia [map of Bacon's Quarter Branch], 30-C-3, n.d., Dimensions: 17 x 32-1/2 in. - 43 x 82 cm.; Scale: 1" = 400'; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 29)
  - Map - The above lots numbering from one to forty nine inclusive, were laid on the lands belonging to the estate of John Graham decd. At theHerbert A. Claiborne Esqr., 1-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: 34-1/4 x 23-3/4 in. - 87 x 61 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, and various colored ink washes on heavy paper with cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 96)
    Drawn By: Micajah Bates
  - Map - [Map showing distances from Richmond along James River to City Point], 29-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: 21-1/4 x 27-3/4 in. - 54 x 71 cm.; Scale: 1" = 300'; Media: Pricking, pencil, and blue wash on heavy paper (damaged; sections missing).; Sheets: 1 (Folder 28)
  - Map - Plan / of / The City of / Richmond / To the Citizens of Richmond this Plan / is respectfully inscribed by their / Obedient Servant / Richard Young, 55-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: Irregular; Scale: None; Media: Ink and Colored inks on heavy paper with cloth backing (in two large pieces - heavily damaged); Sheets: 2 (Folder 95)
    Drawn By: Richard Young
  - Map - [Map showing Civil War fortifications, roads, and houses in the area south of Yorktown to the James River], 12-D-4, n.d., Dimensions: 32 x 23-1/2 in. - 81 x 59 cm.; Scale: 1" = 2500'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper with cloth backing; Sheets: 1 (Folder 28)
  - Map - Rand McNally / Standard Map of / Virginia, 11118-B-5, n.d., Dimensions: 21 x 28-1/4 in. - 53 x 72 cm.; Scale: 1" = 14 miles; Media: Printed map on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: Rand McNally & Co.
  - Map - [Map of Fan District streets showing drainage notations], 13-A-3, n.d., Dimensions: 23-1/2 x 71 in. - 60 x 180 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil, India ink, ad red ink on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
  - Map - Preliminary / Grade Chart / of / Streets in Annexed Territory / South of Cary St. to James River / and West of Tabb Road and Blanton Ave. to R. F. & P. (Belt Line) Railroad, A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 32-1/2 x 40 in. - 83 x 102 cm.; Scale: 1" = 200'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 27)
    Drawn By: Annexed Territory Survey / M.O. Hankins Chief of Survey / Richmond, Va.
  - Map - Map of Shockoe Creek and Vicinity, Between James River and Clay St. / Showing Flood Lines of 1870-77 and 1889., 6-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1.2 x 37 in. - 42 x 94 cm.; Scale: 1" = 100'; Media: 1 India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen, 1 blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 27)
  - Market - Plan of Proposed Market, 13-B-2, [1875], Dimensions: 26 x 37 in. - 66 x 94 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - [Clay Ward Market], 2-B-2 - 12-B-2, 1891, Dimensions: Various; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: 10 India ink on linen sheets with colored ink notations, 2 blueprints; Sheets: 12 (Folder 87)
  - Market - Plan for Fireproof Shed / at Second Meat Market, 43-A-2, 1903, Dimensions: 14 x 46-1/2 in. - 36 x 118 cm.; Scale: 1/2" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - Plan for Arrangement of Stalls / in Second Meat Market, 16-A-1, 1903, Dimensions: 11-1/2 x 21-3/4 in. - 29 x 55 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
    Drawn By: City Eng'r's Office
  - Market - Location of Stalls / Second Vegetable Market, 38-B-1, 1903, Dimensions: 23-1/2 x 20 in. - 60 x 51 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - [Plan of blocks between Broad, Clay, Sixth, and Seventh streets], 26-A-2, 1906, Dimensions: 14-1/4 x 22 in. - 36 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - Third Market Auditorium / for / City of Richmond, [No file number], 1907, Dimensions: 18-1/4 x 29-3/4 in. - 46 x 76 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
    Drawn By: Noland & Baskervill. / Architects & Engineers / Richmond, Va.
  - Market - Third Market Auditorium / for / City of Richmond Alternate First Floor Plan, [No file number], 1907, Dimensions:; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - Third Market Auditorium / for / City of Richmond [elevations and details], [No file number], 1907, Dimensions: 18-1/2 x 29-1/2 in. - 47 x 75 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
    Drawn By: Noland & Baskervill, / Architects & Engineers, / Richmond, Va.
  - Market - 3 Inch Details, / Third Market Auditorium, 16-A-4, 1907, Dimensions: 22-1/4 x 29-3/4 in. - 56 x 76 cm.; Scale: 3" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - City Auditorium / plan showing position of / Trusses, Girders, Rafters, Brackets, Etc., 38-B-2, 1908, Dimensions: 31 x 22 in. - 79 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - Details / of / Girders, Rafters, Brackets Etc. / to Support / Metal Ceiling in City Auditorium [Clay Ward Market], 38-B-2, 1908, Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 35-1/2 in. - 39 x 90 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - City Auditorium Richmond, Va. / Elevations of Walls showing arrangement of Doors and Windows, Interior View and Plan of Furnace Room [Clay Ward Market], 38-B-2, 1908, Dimensions: 19 x 38 in. - 48 x 97 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
    Drawn By: City Eng'rs Office / Richmond, Va.
  - Market - Plan of 'Wheeling Ceilings' Made of Steel for / City Auditorium / Richmond, Virginia, 45-C-3, 1908, Dimensions: 19-1/2 x 31 in. - 49 x 79 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Ink and colored inks on paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
    Drawn By: Drawing by / Wheeling Corrugating Co., / Philadelphia, Pa.
  - Market - City Auditorium, Longitudinal & Transverse Sections Above Ceiling, 30-B-2, 1908, Dimensions: 25 x 24-1/2 in. - 63 x 62 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - City Auditorium / Plan showing position of Pilasters, Windows, Rostrum, etc., 38-B-2, 1908, Dimensions: 19-3/4 x 22-3/4 in. - 50 x 58 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - 2nd Market / Plan for Temporary Vegetable Stalls, 41-B-2, 1909, Dimensions: 20-1/4 x 34-1/2 in. - 51 x 88 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - Auditorium / Part of Longitudinal Section / Showing Lobby, and Gallery Steps., 38-B-2, 1909, Dimensions: 14 x 14 in. - 36 x 36 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - Map of East and West Seventeenth Sts. Between Main and Grace Sts. / Showing Durax Block Paving around Old or First Market Put Down in June, / July, August, and September 1919., 10834-B-1, 1919, Dimensions: 24-1/4 x 42 in. - 62 x 107 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
    Drawn By: Office of the Director of Public Works / Richmond, Va.
  - Market - [Details of reinforcement of roof structure], 38-B-2, n.d., Dimensions: 14-1/2 x 22-1/2 in. - 37 x 57 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - Proposed Station House / in one end of / The Clay Ward Market, 28-D-3, n.d., Dimensions: 13 x 22 in. - 33 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - East Wing of 2nd Vegetable Market / Showing Location of Office and Closet, 18-A-1, n.d., Dimensions: 10 x 12-1/4 in. - 25 x 31 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - Second Meat Market, 16-A-1, n.d., Dimensions: 10 x 23-1/2 in. - 25 x 60 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - Plan of Clay Ward Market, 38-B-2, n.d., Dimensions: 19-3/4 x 23-3/4 in. - 50 x 60 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - [Details of reinforcement of roof structure], 38-B-2, n.d., Dimensions: 18-1/4 x 22-1/2 in. - 46 x 57 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 87)
  - Market - Sketch Showing Changes / at First Meat Market, 46-A-2, n.d., Dimensions: 14 x 20 in. - 36 x 51 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - New Brick Shed / 2nd Market House, 1-B-2, n.d., Dimensions: 35 x 32 in. - 89 x 81 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen with pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Market - Plan / for / Enclosing the 2nd Vegetable Market, 14-B-2, n.d., Dimensions: Irregular; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and brown inks on heavy paper (heavily damaged; in several sections); Sheets: 1 (Folder 30)
  - Non-City - Bridge Over 25th St. Connecting the / Richmond Stemmery with New Factory / for the American Tobacco Co., 41-B-4, 1898, Dimensions: 22-1/2 x 33-3/4 in. - 57 x 86 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Albert F. Huntt / Architect / Richmond
  - Non-City - Proposed Location Fire Escape / The Hotel Richmond / Adatkinson [sic] / Owner, 1-A-4, 1905, Dimensions: 12-1/2 x 18-1/2 in. - 32 x 47 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Pencil and red pencil with in notations on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 32)
    Drawn By: Rejected by Committee on Streets..
  - Non-City - Plan of Property on th East Side / of 14th Street in the City of Richmond / Va belonging to the Gordon Metal Company, 32-B-4, 1905, Dimensions: 19 x 32 in. - 48 x 81 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: T. Crawford Redd & Bro.
  - Non-City - Map / Showing Site / for / Y.M.C.A. Building / Richmond, Va., 19-B-4, 1905, Dimensions: 30-1/4 x 22-1/4 in. - 77 x 56 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Office of Div. Engineer / Richmond Div. C & O Ry.
  - Non-City - Tunnel and Pipeline under Harrison St. form Cold Storage-house / to Bottling-house, 49-A-2, 1906, Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 20-1/4 in. - 39 x 52 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint with red pencil notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Home Brewing Co. Richmond Va.
  - Non-City - Plan of a Proposed Spur Track / for / E. P. Murphy and Son, [No file number], 1909, Dimensions: 13-1/2 x 35 in. - 34 x 89 cm.; Scale: 1" = 40'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: R.F. & P. R. R.
  - Non-City - Plan of Granolithic Steps / for / Residence at N.W. Corner 34th and Clay Sts. / Alternate Plans, 44-B-2, 1909, Dimensions: 31 x 19 in. - 79 x 48 cm.; Scale: 1/2" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
  - Non-City - Plan of a Proposed Coal / Trestle and Yard Layout for / E. P. Murphy & Son. / Richmond, Va., 57-A-1, 1909, Dimensions: 20-1/2 x 34-1/2 in. - 52 x 86 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
  - Non-City - Vault Plan Under / Main Street Sidewalk / Building for / 1st National Bank Bld'g Cor'p / Richmond, Va., 22-D-4, 1911, Dimensions: 36 x 37 in. - 91 x 94 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint with ink notations; Sheets: 2 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Clinton & Russell / Alfred C. Bossom / Associated Architects / New York
  - Non-City - [Basement plan of building at the corner of Jackson and Second streets], 54-B-4, 1912, Dimensions: 16-1/4 x 28-3/4 in. - 41 x 73 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprints with red pencil notations; Sheets: 2 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: [Approval signature by Charles E. Bolling, City Engineer]
  - Non-City - Proposed Extension of Area of / Store Building #312-318 E. Broad St. / Richmond, Virginia / Mr. William C. Schmidt, Owner, 44-A-5, 1912, Dimensions: 12-1/2 x 27 in. - 32 x 68 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 2 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: W. Duncan Lee, Architect / 708 Travelers Bldg. / Richmond, Virginia
  - Non-City - 11th. Street / Proposed Change in Areas - Property / North-West Corner of 11th. & Main Sts., 45-A-5, 1912, Dimensions: 16-1/4 x 23-1/4 in. - 41 x 59 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Approved / Chas. E Bolling / City Engineer / Rapheal Levy Owner
  - Non-City - Stores for Broad St. Bank Cor 6th & Broad St., 53-B-4, 1912, Dimensions: 14 x 8-1/2 in. - 35 x 22 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Richmond Structural Steel Co., Inc. / Richmond, Va.
  - Non-City - Sketch Showing Areaways for Store Buildings / Cor. Of Broad and Laurel St., 76-A-2, 1912, Dimensions: 10-1/2 x 30-1/2 in. - 26 x 77 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 32)
    Drawn By: Asbury & Whitehurst / Architects & Engineers / #1105 Mutual Building / Richmond, Virginia
  - Non-City - Drawing Showing Areas / to / Stores to be Erected at the / North West Cor. Broad & 6th Sts., / Richmond, Va. / for the / Broad St. Bank, 55-B-4, 1912, Dimensions: 10-3/4 x 35 in. - 27 x 89 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint with red ink notations; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
  - Non-City - [British American Tobacco Co. plant on Lombardy Street], [No file number], 1912, Dimensions: 30 x 41 in. - 76 x 104 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 3 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Francisco & Jacobus / Consulting Engineers / 200 Fifth Avenue, New York City
  - Non-City - The American Tobacco Co. Richmond, Va. / P.H. Mayo & Bro. Branch [bridge over 26th St.], 40-A-6, 1912, Dimensions: 20-3/4 x 33 in. - 53 x 84 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: 1 blueprint, 1 pencil on tracing paper; Sheets: 2 (Folder 32)
  - Non-City - Partial Plan of Basement - Lyric Theater B'l'd'g. / Richmond, Va - Showing Arrangement of / Boiler Room, Etc., 48-A-5, 1912, Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 29-1/2 in. - 42 x 75 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Blueprint with ink notations (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: C.K. Howell Arch't. / Richmond, Va.
  - Non-City - Detail Construction Tunnel and Bridges / Between 207-9 N. Fourth St. and 403-5 E. Broad St. / Richmond, Va., for I. H. Kautmann, 57-B-4, 1912, Dimensions: 19 x 23-3/4 in. - 48 x 60 cm.; Scale: 1/2" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Albert F. Huntt / Arch't.
  - Non-City - Convent and Chapel / for the / St. Mary's Benedictine Institute / Richmond, Va. [plot plan], 58-B-4, 1912, Dimensions: 30-1/2 x 40 in. - 77 x 102 cm.; Scale: 1/16" = 1'; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 31)
    Drawn By: Maginnis & Walsh / Architects Boston Mass